Contact

+923052092168 (Mobile) faisalmengrani@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-faisal-b4691889 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Microsoft Excel Microsoft Word Team Leadership

Languages

English (Full Professional)
Urdu (Native or Bilingual)

Honors-Awards
Graduation Completion
Master Degree

Muhammad Faisal

Supply Chain (Import) & Finance Professional

Summary

Have more than 6 years of professional experience in the field of accounting and finance. Being a key player in the corporate environment, I am a confident person with the sense of business ethics. With my academic record, I possess knowledge and expertise in the field of accounting with a solid grip on financial concepts.

Due to my resilient character and meticulous nature, I have the ability to work on multiple domains. Even though being a finance professional when I was handed over the responsibility of Import side management of the company, I made sure to pass the hurdles with flying colors. It is my pride that I have always been an active team player with professional attitude. No matter how hard the circumstance are I know how to endure under extreme pressure.

Experience

DANY Technologies Inc. Finance Executive November 2017 - Present (2 years 6 months) Karachi

Designed financial budget 2020 as well as 2019 and helped the company in cutting cost over import and export, internal audit for FY 2019 with ISO team supervision, enhanced payroll management software, supervised internees and finance team while maintaining their progress report, prepared financial analysis report 2019-20, financial planning after change in import regulation guiding the company to save extra cost over shipments, completed 5 months pending financial accounts of the company within 1 month.

Additional Work: Cost-effective transportation analysis and freight management, company warehouse management, dealing with custom issues in clearing and forwarding, started computerized records of containers and inventory management leaving the manual work, helped in reducing human error in supply chain management up to 70%

RAH Securities Pvt Limited Senior Finance Officer January 2013 - October 2017 (4 years 10 months)

Karachi Stock Exchange

Planning and managing financial budgets along with expense audit as per SOP, resolved

compliance inquires that were received from SECP within 8 hours, prepared computerized 2 years pending financial accounts within 2 weeks, due to strong PR relations helped the company many times in compliance matters especially that were received from PSX and CDC, received promotion twice due to superior performance.

Education

Khadim Ali Shah Bukhari Institute of Technology

Master of Business Administration (MBA), Finance (2014 - 2017)

Karachi University

Bachelor of Commerce (BCom), Accounting and Finance · (2012 - 2014)

Government National College Karachi Intermediate, Pre Engineering (2008 - 2010)

Mama Baby Care School

Matriculation, Computer Science · (2007 - 2008)